# **Ian Chua**

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

CONTACT: 022 621 0388 EMAIL: ianchuajl@hotmail.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-jl-chua/

GITHUB: https://github.com/ian-jl-chua

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English
- Mandarin (spoken)
- · Cantonese (spoken)

#### **ABOUT ME**

Kia ora, my name is Ian. I recently graduated from Dev Academy (2023) as a Full Stack Web Developer.

I have been in the finance industry for 5 years, working as a Service Consultant, and later as a Banking Consultant at ANZ. The encounters I had during the pandemic sparked my interest in the tech field, motivating me to learn more about technology in finance.

Moving forward, I am keen to use my newfound skills to support others on their financial journey.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

Student – Full Stack Web Development | Dev Academy Aotearoa January 2023 – April 2023

- This is a 15- week intensive Web Development course that covers technical skills needed for a modern Web Development Stack, and soft skills like teamwork, empathy and self-awareness.
- The technical skills covered include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Redux, Knex, SQlite3, TypeScript, Jest. These were applied in various challenges given while Pair Programming during weekdays, and in Friday group projects where we worked collaboratively in small agile teams.
- The course also involved working in various team environments, empathizing with others, and learning how to give and receive growth feedback.
- For our final group project, we worked on a game idea similar to Gartic phone, where we
  implemented all the skills we've learnt from the course. As the Git Lead for the project, I was
  responsible for ensuring the commits were merged properly and resolving any conflicts during the
  merge. I also see the benefits of having a solid plan during the early stages of a project, as this
  makes delegating workload more efficient.

## Banking Consultant | ANZ South Dunedin September 2018 - Present

- Multi-skilled, able to cover the counter when a Service Consultant is away to support the team.
- With good product knowledge, I am able to proactively add value to each customer interaction.
- Appointed as a Digital Champion for the branch.
- Building good customer relations by providing guidance to the customers. Helping them understand good account conduct.
- I was a KANA delegator during the Covid Lockdown distributing and managing communication between my colleagues and customers in the Dunedin region.
- During the second Covid Lockdown I held the fort for the team, as a few of my colleagues were unable to set up to work from home, for the Broker Hand over project.
- Health and Safety Officer for the branch (2022)

Service Consultant | ANZ Northwest Auckland March 2017 - September 2018

Copy-Center Specialist | Warehouse Stationery June 2015 - March 2017

Apprentice Builder
June 2014 - Dec 2014

#### **EDUCATION**

LEVEL 6 WEB DEVELOPMENT TRAINING SCHEME | Dev Academy Aotearoa January 2023 – April 2023

**LEVEL 4 CERTIFICATE OF CARPENTRY | UNITEC** June 2013 – June 2014

LEVEL 3 NCEA

### <u>OTHER INTEREST</u>

- Board games with friends
- · Learning how to cook various dishes
- · Meditation and yoga
- Cats

#### **REFEREE UPON REQUEST**